intuitcanada.com 2011-06-24

# Privacy Policy | Intuit® Canada

|    

At Intuit, we pride ourselves in our commitment to protecting your privacy. We want you to know how personal information about you is used, collected and disclosed.

Personal information is information that can be used to identify or contact you individually, and other information required to provide the products and services you have requested. Typically, this includes your name, e-mail address, mailing address, telephone number and credit card number. It does not include contact information about a person in their business capacity, such as the name, title, business address, or telephone number of an employee of an organization.

---  
|   
---  
---  
  
In order to fulfill requests for personal information records or to answer any questions or address any concerns individuals may have about privacy, Intuit Canada has designated a privacy officer. In addition to answering inquiries, the privacy officer is also responsible for ensuring that legislation and privacy practices and related procedures are being met.

All inquiries or complaints regarding privacy should be directed to the privacy officer by mail, fax or e-mail at the addresses below. Inquiries will be responded to in accordance with the legislated timeframes.

**MAIL**  
Intuit Canada   
Attention: Privacy Officer  
7008 Roper Road  
Edmonton, AB   
T6B 3H2

**FAX**  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
FAX: 1-888-829-1724

|   
---  

To change your privacy preferences and personal information, please [complete this form](http://anon.intuit-canada.speedera.net.edgesuite.net/anon.intuit-canada/www.intuit.ca/quickbooks/2007/Privacy_Preferences_Change_Form.pdf) and fax (toll-free) or mail it to us at:

**MAIL**  
Intuit Canada   
Attention: Privacy Officer  
7008 Roper Road  
Edmonton, AB   
T6B 3H2

**FAX**  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
FAX: 1-888-829-1724

TurboTax online application users should make any updates, modifications, or deletions to their tax return information directly through the Web site. There are certain changes that cannot be made to ensure that only one tax return is prepared per registration. The TurboTax License and Services Agreement contains further details.

|   
|   
---  
| 

## Intuit® Canada's 10 Privacy Principles

Intuit's 10 Privacy Principles are modeled after the principles established in Canada's Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, or PIPEDA. Read more about them on this page.

   1\. Accountability      
   2\. Identifying Purposes  
   3\. Consent      
   4\. Limiting Collection  
   5\. Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention      
   6\. Accuracy  
   7\. Safeguards      
   8\. Openness  
   9\. Individual Access      
  10\. Challenging Compliance  
  
---  
|    

---  
|  | 

## Accountability  
  
---  
  
Intuit is responsible for maintaining and protecting personal information about you in our care or control. We have designated a Privacy Officer who is accountable for compliance with our policies and PIPEDA.

We sometimes use outside companies, called third parties, to help us provide the product or service you request. Regardless of the location of these third parties, Intuit requires these third parties to comply with Canadian privacy legislation and Intuit's Privacy Principles. Certain third parties may be located in the United States and therefore may also be subject to US legislation.

|   
| 

## Identifying Purposes  
  
---  
| 

You have a right to know how your information will be used. We will explain why we need you information before or when we collect it, if the purpose is not already clear. We will assume that the purpose is clearly identified when we use your personal information to:

  * Fulfill your product or service request.
  * Process your payment, including recurring payments when you request them.
  * Update you as to the status of your order.
  * Alert you to important product revisions or updates.
  * Ensure that you are properly registered to receive technical support for certain products.

Intuit may use your personal information for secondary purposes such as:

  * Telling you about special discounts or offers on Intuit upgrades or new products and services.
  * Inviting you to participate in customer surveys or other opinion-gathering devices.
  * Providing you with special offers from other companies made available to Intuit customers.
  * Telling you about educational events, such as training seminars, conferences and online training sessions.

We may also display ads in the TurboTax application for Intuit or third party services that we feel may be of interest. These ads are not targeted in any way or based on your personal information or behavior through the Web site.

If you sign up for the TurboTax online application, we will collect tax return information required to assist you in completing and filing your tax return. Tax return information is the personal information you provide for the specific purpose of preparing a tax return using the TurboTax online application. Intuit uses your tax return information to:

  * Provide you with online tax preparation
  * Facilitate the electronic filing of your tax return

Intuit does not use your tax return information to market other Intuit or third-parties products or services.

Aggregate data is general information about groups of customers, and does not identify individual customers. Intuit may combine your information with that of other individuals to create aggregate data which we will use to improve our products and services and develop new ones. For example, we may tell a third party how many people purchased a certain product, but not that you personally purchased a specific item.

Intuit will not disclose your personal information to any third parties without your consent, except under the following limited circumstances:

  * As is reasonably required to fulfill your service or product requirements, provided such third parties shall be bound to appropriate privacy requirements.
  * To comply with a legal process such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena, court order or law enforcement request.
  * To resolve a contractual dispute regarding your use of an Intuit product, service or related account, or if your account may be involved in illegal activities.
  * To protect the personal safety of other users or members of the public in an emergency.

| 

## Consent  
  
---  
  
Intuit will only collect, use and disclose your personal information with your knowledge and consent, except where permitted or as required by law. Intuit will not rent, sell, or otherwise distribute your personal information without your permission. Your consent to use your personal information will be implied for the following purposes:

  * Fulfilling your product or service request.
  * Updating you as to the status of your order.
  * Alerting you to important product revisions or updates.
  * Ensuring that you are properly registered to receive technical support for certain products.

You control any future secondary use of your personal information, such as sharing it with marketers. You can prevent future secondary use of your information by "opting out" when Intuit collects your information or at any time by simply contacting us. Opting out only applies to the secondary purposes because we may need to contact you regarding the usability of your product or alert you of important product revisions or updates.

For users of the TurboTax online application, personal information is not required to try the service or to browse the Web site. The full benefits of the TurboTax online application are reserved for registered users. To receive them, or to participate in online activities, such as surveys and contests, we will ask you to provide certain personal information so that we can identify you.

By signing up for the TurboTax online application, you are not obligated to provide any tax return information. However, if you do not provide complete information when preparing your tax return, you will not have complete use of the service. That may significantly impact the accuracy of your tax return. Personal information is necessary to complete and file a tax return using the TurboTax online application, so that we can process payment and registration for the service.

To change your privacy preferences, please complete the [Personal Information Change Form](http://anon.intuit-canada.speedera.net.edgesuite.net/anon.intuit-canada/www.intuit.ca/quickbooks/2007/Privacy_Preferences_Change_Form.pdf) located here and mail it to us or fax it toll-free to the following:

**INTUIT CANADA ULC**  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
7008 Roper Road  
Edmonton, AB T6B 3H2

FAX: 1-888-829-1724

Please note that if you are posting personal information on an online community, this information is publicly available and Intuit has no further obligations to maintain the privacy of that information.

|   
| 

## Limiting Collection  
  
---  
| 

Intuit will only collect personal information for the purposes we've identified or for the primary uses as we've described above. We will always do this fairly and legally. There are several ways we'll collect information:

  * Through the purchase of products or services.
  * Through registrations of purchased products, services or technical support.
  * Through completed Intuit rebate or coupon certificates that are filled out and mailed in.
  * Through requests for information.
  * From third parties who you authorized to share such information.

Whenever we ask for information that is not required for us to provide the product or service you requested, we will mark those questions appropriately as optional.

**Cookies**  
Intuit uses a variety of Web technologies on our Web sites. Among these are cookies, which are pieces of information that our Web sites provide to your browser. Cookies allow us to track overall site usage and determine areas users prefer. Cookies also allow us to customize your visit to our Web sites by recognizing you when you return. Cookies cannot be used to see any other data on your computer, nor can they determine your e-mail address or identity.

Most browsers accept and maintain cookies by default. Check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preference. You can choose to decline cookies while at our Web site, but this may limit your ability to access certain areas of the Web site.

To purchase and download products from Intuit.ca and to use the TurboTax online application, your browser must be able to accept cookie. Cookies are required for these services to authenticate registered users and to provide access to certain areas of our Web sites that are available to limited registered users only. Cookies are deleted when you close your browser, as well; this authentication becomes invalid after a certain period of time.

With or without cookies, our Web sites track usage data, such as the source address that a page request is coming from, your IP address or domain name, the date and time of the page request, the referring Web site (if any) and other parameters in the URL. We use this data to better understand Web site usage in the aggregate so that we know what areas of our Web site users prefer. This information is stored in log files and is used for aggregated and statistical reporting. This log information is not linked to personal information gathered elsewhere on the site.

Intuit Web sites may include banner advertisements or links to third-party Web sites. Advertising networks that serve ads may assign different cookies to you. Those cookies may be used to track your involvement with the advertising site. You may choose not to accept these cookies. Intuit does not control these parties, and you should review their privacy policies to learn more about what, why and how they collect and use personal information.

**Co-Branded Sites**  
Our co-branded sites are clearly identified by both an Intuit and a third-party logo. Intuit Canada's Web sites may provide links to third-party Web sites, such as those of online advertisers and companies which have been carefully screened by Intuit. On these sites, third-parties and Intuit may collect information about you. Intuit is not responsible for the actions of these third-parties, and Intuit's collection of personal information is in accordance with our privacy practices. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to learn more about how they collect, use and share personal information.  
  
| 

## Limiting Use, Disclosure, and Retention  
  
---  
  
Intuit will not use or disclose your personal information other than for the purposes for which it was collected, with the exception of receiving your consent or as permitted or required by law. When providing information in response to a legal inquiry or order, we will verify its validity and only disclose information that is legally required.

Intuit is a multi-national company and as such, some personal information may be shared within Intuit and stored in countries outside of Canada. Currently, some personal information, excluding tax return information, may be stored or processed in the United States and therefore may be subject to US legislation. Tax return information remains in Canada unless you give Intuit your express consent for it to be transferred and/or stored outside of Canada. 'Tax return information' excludes non-personally identifiable information concerning your use of the Intuit tax products -- e.g. which screens you viewed.

Intuit will keep personal information only as long as necessary for the identified purposes or as required by law. Intuit will follow internally set guidelines and use care in the disposal, destruction, or de-identification of personal information to prevent unauthorized parties from gaining access to personal information.

|   
| 

## Accuracy  
  
---  
| 

Intuit will keep your personal information as accurate, complete and up-to-date as necessary for the identified purposes for which it was collected. We encourage you to let us know if your contact information changes.

To change your privacy preferences and personal information, please go to Updating your privacy preferences and personal information.

TurboTax online application users should make any updates, modifications, or deletions to their tax return information directly through the Web site. There are certain changes that cannot be made to ensure that only one tax return is prepared per registration. The TurboTax License and Services Agreement contains further details.  
  
| 

## Safeguards  
  
---  
  
We protect personal information and tax return information in our possession and control by using security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. Intuit works to protect personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized alteration using industry-recognized security safeguards. We restrict internal access to personal information to select members of Intuit's staff.

If you are using the TurboTax online application, we encrypt your tax return information and store it safely on our secure servers, which reside in Canada. Intuit does not store any tax return information outside of Canada. Unless you give us specific consent, you are the only one who will have access to your own tax return information, subject to legislated exceptions.

|   
| 

## Openness  
  
---  
| 

This policy is an overview of information about our policies and practices relating to the management of personal information. Any changes or modifications to our privacy practices will be posted in this policy for 30 days before they take effect. We will not make retroactive changes to the practices associated with your personal information without your consent.  
  
| 

## Individual Access  
  
---  
  
Subject to exceptions as permitted or mandated by law and subject to your written request for such information, Intuit will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information and give you access to that information. You have the right to challenge the accuracy and completeness of your information and have it amended as appropriate.

|   
| 

## Challenging Compliance  
  
---  
| 

You may contact us with questions, comments or complaints regarding Intuit's privacy policy and practices. Please contact Intuit's Privacy Officer, whose contact details are located at the top of this page.
